Antonio Romano - Laboratorio di Fonetica Sperimentale “Arturo Genre”, Università degli Studi di Torino. http://www.lfsag.unito.it/EVALITA2014/index.html
March 2014.

The EVALITA task "Human and Machine Dialect Identification from Natural Speech and Artificial Stimuli" is manyfold.
Three tasks are intended to test human abilities (listening tests) and a fourth experimental setting is designed for automatic systems of language identification.
The execution of the listening tests should be preceeded by the installation of the PRAAT software (http://www.fon.hum.uva.nl/praat/) and the creation of a HMDI folder under C:\ of the PC you are working on. Please put in this folder the HMDI.txt file and the wavefiles extracted from the HMDI.zip file.

HMDI is a task aiming at testing human abilities to identify languages from short speech samples. Download and run the pps file "HMDI1-EVALITA2014_ENG.pps" before starting the listening test. Launch PRAAT, get the HMDI.txt file in the object list and run it*.

HMDI_DIA is a task mainly intended for listeners living in Italy and it is aimed at testing their abilities to identify dialectal varieties. Download and run the pps file "HMDI_DIA.pps" before starting the listening test. Launch PRAAT, get the HMDI.txt file in the object list and run it*.

HMDI_TON aims at testing the ability of Italian listeners in identifying dialectal varieties relying on just prosodic values extracted from real sentences. Download and run the pps file "HMDI_TON.pps" before starting the listening test. Launch PRAAT, get the HMDI_TON.txt file in the object list and run it*.

*Do not forget to “Extract Results” and save the ResultsMFC object as a textfile (with your initials) and send it to: antonio.romano@unito.it (Thank you for your help!)

The same samples in the folder C:\HMDI may be used for testing machine performances in identifying languages and dialects after a training of your LID/AID system on longer samples and/or samples uttered by other speakers. Download HMDI_TRAINING.zip and make a copy of the training wavefiles in a HMDI_TRAINING folder.
Please report results to: antonio.romano@unito.it
Research teams interested in testing their LID/AID system may also run it on telephonic or noisy samples available in the HMDI_NOISY.zip file.